testcraft.com 2012-09-19

# Ingenious Group - Privacy Policy

Ingenious Group, Inc. respects the privacy of our customers, business partners, employees, job applicants, and other visitors to our websites ([http://www.testcraft.com](http://www.testcraft.com/) and www.ingeniousgroup.com ) who may choose to provide us with their personal information. We recognize the need for appropriate protections and management of personal information that you provide to us. This Privacy Statement will assist you to understand what types of information we may collect, how that information may be used, and with whom the information may be shared. 

Ingenious Group, Inc. is in compliance with the U.S. Department of Commerce Safe Harbor requirements regarding the transfer of personal information from European Union member countries to the United States. The principles of Safe Harbor compliance are notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access and enforcement.

Ingenious Group has been awarded TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with TRUSTe’s program requirements including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information.  TRUSTe’s mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at Ingenious Group, Inc. P.O. Box 317 New Hartford, CT 06057 or by phone at +1 (860) 738-2231.  If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

## Information We Collect

Personal Information is information that can be used to identify or contact a specific individual, such as a name, address, telephone number or email address. Ingenious Group may collect certain personal information from customers, business partners, and employees when signing up for our forum, requesting information, contacting support, or signing up for our newsletter. Ingenious Group does not collect personal information when you visit Ingenious Group’s web sites unless you choose to provide such personal information.

Customers and Partners: On Ingenious Group web sites you can, register products, request information, subscribe to marketing or support materials, register to a secure extranet site to obtain access to product information, support, services and training. The types of personal information you provide to us on these pages may include name, address, phone number, e-mail address, user IDs and passwords, , and contact preferences. 

### How Personal Information is Used?

Ingenious Group will use personal information to provide customers and business partners with information and services and to help us better understand your needs and interests. Specifically, we use your information to help you complete creating your account for our forum, to communicate with you, to send you newsletters or marketing emails, provide you with information you requested and to provide ongoing service and support. Occasionally we may use your information to contact you to complete surveys that we use for marketing and quality assurance purposes. Personal information collected online may be combined with information you provide to Ingenious Group through other sources such as trade shows or seminars.

However, if you request information on any of our products/services, Ingenious Group may provide your information to third party distributors and resellers who may subsequently contact you directly to purchase such products/services. In these instances, you will not have the opportunity to opt out of having your information shared with these third party distributors and resellers.

### Newsletters

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your email address to send the newsletter to you.  Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe.  Please see the “Choice and Opt-out” section.

Some of Ingenious Group’s websites use on-line chat forums and blogs that are made available to our website and service users. You should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages.  We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. 

When using the forum on our site you are able to create a public profile, the information that you are able to provide is instant messenger user names, email address, location, occupation and interests. As stated above we are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you submit within this area. Except as provided in this Statement, Ingenious Group does not use your personal information for a purpose other than the stated purpose for which such information is collected.

Personal information given to Ingenious Group may be transferred within Ingenious Group across state and country borders for efficient data consolidation, storage and simplified information management. 

### Who Does Ingenious Group Share Personal Information With?

Ingenious Group may contract with third party service providers and suppliers, such as web hosting companies, or other service organizations required to perform requested services, etc., to deliver partial or complete products, services and solutions for our customers. Ingenious Group may share personal information with its service providers and suppliers for the sole purpose and only to the extent needed to support the customers’ business needs. Service providers and suppliers are required to keep confidential the personal information received from Ingenious Group and may not use it for any purpose other than as originally intended.

Third party vendors, service providers and suppliers receiving personal information are expected to apply the same level of privacy protection as contained in this Privacy Statement.

Except as provided above, Ingenious Group will not share, sell, rent, or trade your personal information with third parties.

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site

### Choice and Consent

Ingenious Group does not require customers, business partners or non-employee visitors to Ingenious Group websites to provide Ingenious Group with personal information. The decision to provide personal information is voluntary. If you do not wish to provide the personal information requested, however, you may not be able to proceed with particular activities or receive the full benefit for which the personal information is being requested.

 ** _If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by emailing us at[optout@ingeniousgroup.com](mailto:optout@ingeniousgroup.com) or by sending your opt-out notification to Ingenious Group, Inc. P.O. Box 317 New Hartford, CT 06057_**

### Data Quality

Ingenious Group makes efforts to keep your personal information accurate. We have implemented technology, processes and policies to maintain data accuracy and integrity. We will provide you with access to your information, and in some cases may make reasonable efforts to provide you with online access and the opportunity to change or delete any inaccuracies within your information. To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access to your data. If you have a forum account you may correct or delete any inaccuracies within your information by logging into your account. Otherwise you may email us at [privacy@ingenious.com](mailto:privacy@ingenious.com).  We will respond to your request to access within 30 days. 

Ingenious Group will not process personal information in a way that is incompatible with the purposes for which it has been collected or authorized by the individual, or as required by applicable law.

### Security

Ingenious Group is committed to making reasonable efforts to secure the personal data you choose to provide us. To protect the privacy of any personal information you may have provided to us, we employ reasonable industry-standard controls including physical and logical access controls, network security devices, and anti-virus protection. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can email us at [privacy@ingeniousgroup.com](mailto:privacy@ingeniousgroup.com).

### Other Information

Ingenious Group collects and/or logs Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, Internet domain names, the web browser and operating system used to access the Ingenious Group web site, the files visited, the time spent in each file, and the time and date of each visit.

Ingenious Group may also use cookies on some of its web sites. Cookies are identifiers that can be sent from a web site via your browser to be placed on your computers hard drive. You may elect not to accept cookies by changing the privacy or other settings on your web browser. Choosing not to accept or utilize cookies may prevent you from accessing or using certain features of our web sites. The information collected from the use of cookies is used and analyzed to improve Ingenious Group’s web sites, information and product and services and to personalize your web-browsing experience. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.

Ingenious Group uses the services of third party vendors to help us measure the effectiveness of our advertising and how visitors use ingeniousgroup.com and testcraft.com. To do this, we may use cookies and other tokens provided by third parties on our sites. The type of information we collect includes the pages visited, navigation patterns, time spent on our site, etc. This information helps us learn things such as what product information is of most interest to our customers, and what kinds of offers our customers may like to see. Although our third party vendors log the information coming from our site on our behalf, Ingenious Group determines how that data may and may not be used and may not offer opt-out functionality for this information collected on these websites. We do not have access or control over these third party cookies.  Third party cookies are not covered by our privacy policy. 

### Links to Non-Ingenious Group Web Sites and Third Parties

The Ingenious Group web sites may provide links to third-party web sites for your convenience and information. If you access those links, you will leave the Ingenious Group web site. Ingenious Group does not control those sites or their privacy practices, which may differ from our own. We do not endorse or make any representations about third party web sites. The personal data you choose to give to unrelated third parties is not covered by the Ingenious Group Privacy Statement. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of any company or website before submitting your personal information. Some third party companies may choose to share their personal data with Ingenious Group; that sharing is governed by that third party company’s privacy policy.

### Verification

Ingenious Group will engage in periodic self-assessment to verify that it continues to be in compliance with this Privacy Statement. Contact Information

_If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Statement or believe that the privacy of your personal information has not been respected, you may make a written submission to the attention of Ingenious Groupâ€™s Legal Administration Office, 105 Lakeshore Drive, New Hartford, CT 06057._

### Dispute Resolution

Ingenious Group agrees to handle all disputes involving the transfer of personal data from the EU to the U.S. using the Better business bureau Online dispute resolution procedures applicable to Safe Harbor.

Except as provided above, dispute resolution for all other individuals shall be in accordance with applicable law. 

### Changes to this Statement

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently.  If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.
